Guide to the Michael Polanyi Papers 1900-1975
University of Chicago Library
- Series II: Notes
  - Subseries 2: Author
    - B, Karl Britton D. W. Brogan Charles V. W. Brooks Lloyd A. Brown Lenny Bruce Rudolf Bultmann Jacob Burckhardt Edmund Burke D. Burlingham J. B. Bury M. Butenko Samuel Butler Herbert Butterfield F. J. J. Buytendijk Major Byron (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - C, Norman Campbell S. Cannizzaro W. B. Cannon Hadley Cantril Justice Cardoza Rudolf Carnap Edward H. Carr E. Cassirer N. Chiaromonte G. Childe (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - C, R. M. Chisholm Noam Chomsky E. M. Chossudowsky (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - C, Galeazzo Ciano E. Claparede W. K. Clifford Morris R. Cohen G. D. H. Cole Samuel Coleridge R. G. Collingwood Alistair Cooke Copernicus F. C. Copleston Gabor Cossa Maurice Cranston O. G. S. Crawford Ernest Crocker A. C. Crombie J. G. Crowther (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - D, Albert Dalcq Honoré Daumier Simone de Beauvoir J. De Boer Democritus René Descartes Friedrich Dessauer John Dewey Charles Dickens Henry D. Dickinson (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - D, Diogenes P. A. M. Dirac Maurice Dobb S. Dobrin Peter Doig Rene Dubos Pierre Duhem E. F. M. Durbin (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - E, Ralph Eaton Ilya Ehrenburg Jan Ehrenwald Albert Einstein Mircea Eliade T. S. Eliot J. Elliotson W. N. Elsasser C. W. Eriksen Erwin A. Esper Leonard Euler E. E. Evans-Pritchard (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - F, Françoise Faber M. S. Farbman Herbert Feigl Raymond Firth Irving Fisher R. A. Fisher Constantine Fitzgibbon P. Sargant Florence M. Fortes H. Munro Fox Max Frisch Kurt von Fritz J. F. Fulton (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - G, Alan H. Gardiner Ortega y Gasset F. H. George A. Gesell C. V. Gheorghiu K. Gibberd Edward Gibbon J. J. Gibson André Gide C. C. Gillispie E. Gilman Nicholas Gimes Etienne Gilson A. D. Glanville E. Glover M. Gluckman John Godley (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - G, Goethe I. J. Good Geoffrey Gorer A. W. Gouldner Alexander Gray J. S. Gray Marjorie Grene Adolf Grünbaum Luther Gulick Gumbel (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - H, J. A. Bierens de Haan Kurt Hahn C. Haldane J. S. Haldane Elie Halevy Philip P. Hallie Barbara Hammond John L. Hammond N. R. Hanson D. W. Harding Alister Hardy G. H. Hardy R. M. Hare S. C. Harland Romano Harré G. Hart H. L. A. Hart Liddell Hart A. H. Hastorf F. A. Hayek D. O. Hebb (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - H, L. Heck G. W. Hegel H. L. F. Helmholtz C. G. Hempel David Henderson J. G. von Herder Gordon Hewart E. P. Hilgard Thomas Hobbes A. M. Hocart P.H. d'Holbach J. Holloway S. J. Holmes Erik von Holst Homer (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - H, Sir J. D. Hooker Karen Horney A. E. Housman L. E. Hubbard R. Hughes Clark L. Hull George Humphrey Evan Hunter Edmund Husserl Julian Huxley (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - I-J, Orvis C. Irwin William James Storm Jameson Sir James Jeans G. Jefferson N. Jeffreys Otto Jespersen C. E. M. Joad Harry M. Johnson Hewlett Johnson H. Spencer Jones J. W. Jones Mansel Jones C. G. Jung (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - K, Joseph Kälin Immanuel Kant David Katz Walter Kaufmann (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - K, Jacques Kayser Paul Kecskemeti W. N. Kellogg Peter Kende Kenneth Keniston C. S. Kenny Johannes Kepler J. M. Keynes Gregory A. Kimble A. W. Kinglake Rudyard Kipling E. L. Kirchner George Klein C. Kluckhohn (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - K, Arthur Koestler K. Koffka Eugen Kogon Ivo Kohler Wolfgang Köhler K. Kottenhoff Alexandre Koyre I. Krechevsky Thomas Kuhn (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - L, G. A. de Laguna R. D. Laing Charles Lamb Johannes Lange Susanne K. Langer Pierre Laplace K. S. Lashley Lancelot Lawton W. E. H. Lecky G. W. Leibnitz (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - L, N. Lenin W. F. Leopold Hermann Levy Lucien Levy-Bruhl Kurt Lewin Clarence I. Lewis W. A. Lewis H. S. Liddell (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - L, Lord Lindsay Leonard Linsky Ralph Linton Walter Lippmann John Locke Otto Loewi Konrad Lorenz H. A. Lorentz F. Lorimer R. H. Lowie T. D. Lysenko (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - M, William McDougall D. V. McGranahan N. Machiavelli Admiral Mahan N. R. F. Maier Sir Henry Sumner Miane Bronislaw Malinowski John M. Manly Jacob Marshak J. H. Massermann Henri Matisse W. Somerset Maugham James Clerk Maxwell Margaret Mead P. B. Medawar Friedrich Meinecke Philip Melanchthon J. A. Melrose Robert K. Merton Albert Michelson (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - M, André Michotte N. Micklem Idézet G. Miklos J. S. Mill George A. Miller Richard von Mises Ian I. Mitroff Joseph-Marie Montmasson C. W. Morris W. A. Mozart Carl Murchison Gilbert Murray (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - N-O, S. F. Nadel Joseph Needham Ernest Newman John Henry Cardinal Newman Max Newman Harold Nicolson Reinhold Niebuhr Paul Niggli F. S. C. Northrop Michael Oakeshott John Oman J. Robert Oppenheimer W. Ostwald (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - P, C. F. A. Pantin Paracelsus Sir J. H. Parsons Talcott Parsons J. R. Partington R. Pearl D. F. Pears Karl Pearson Wilder Penfield C. V. Peursen O. Pfungst F. A. Philbrick Charles Louis Philippe Jean Piaget (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - P, Pablo Picasso Maurice Pirenne Max Planck Arnold Plant Plato Henri Poincaré Sir Fredrick Pollock Georg Polya Karl Popper F. M. Powicke Derek J. de Solla Price H. H. Price Terence Prittie (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Q-R, W. V. Quine Gerhard Rasmussen Hermann Rauschning Charles E. Raven Herbert Read G. Revesz Quentin Reynolds Rheticus Willis B. Rice I. A. Richards (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - R, M. Richardson Rainer Maria Rilke Gerhard P. Ritter D. H. Robertson E. A. G. Robinson Joan Robinsonq J. J. Rousseau Bertrand Russell E. S. Russell H. N. Russell (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - S, Antoine de Saint-Exupery Andrew Salter S. Sambursky Edward Sapir Jean-Paul Sartre Joseph Sauveur Martin Scheerer Max Scheler Frank Schlesinger J. A. Schumpeter Leopold Schwarzschild John Scott Michael Scriven (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - S, Ignaz Seipel R. S. Shankland Hugh Shearnon A. D. Sheffield P. B. Shelley Sir Charles Sherrington Edward Shils Charles Singer B. F. Skinner J. J. C. Smart Howard K. Smith J. N. Smith Lillian Smith (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - S, Maynard Smith T. B. Smith A. Smits J. C. Smuts Bruno Snell F. Soddy R. V. Southwell C. Spearman Herbert Spencer Roger W. Sperry Joseph Stalin Sir Josiah C. Stamp Franz Stampfl L. Susan Stebbing K. Steer Sir James Fitzjames Stephen Karin Stephen Charles L. Stevenson G. F. Stout John Strachey E. B. Strauss Leo Strauss Igor Stravinsky P. F. Strawson Count Stürgkh Z. Stypulkowski H. Sutherland (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - T, Alfred Tarski F. Sherwood Taylor Dylan Thomas Denys Thompson L. L. Thurstone Paul Tillich Rudolf Tischner E. C. Tolman Stephen Toulmin George M. Trevelyan Lionel Trilling W. Trotter (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - U-V, Stephen Ullman J. O. Urmson Peter Usley Paul Valerie Immanuel Velikovsky G. N. A. Vesey Sir Geoffrey Vickers Mark Vischniak Karl Vossler (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - W, C. H. Waddington Friedrich Waismann A. Wald Graham Wallas W. H. Walsh A. F. Watts Richard M. Weaver Max Weber Simone Weil J. R. Weinberg Paul Weiss Viktor von Weizsäcker Max Wertheimer George P. West Hermann Weyl W. M. Wheeler William Whewell (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - W-Z, A. N. Whitehead Norbert Wiener Eugene P. Wigner Basil Willey Charles Williams R. A. Wilson R. S. Woodworth Virginia Woolf William Wordsworth Orville and Wilbur Wright H. G. Wyatt William Butler Yeats Catherine York Lin Yutang Ernst Zinner Carl Zuckmayer (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 3: File Cards
    - A-W, Artists on Art Gaston Bachelard A. J. Bachrach William Barret Reinhard Bendix Rene Berthelot Maine de Biran Erwin Boring K. E. Boulding J. Bronovski Jerome S. Bruner Kenneth Burke Edwin Burit Clinical Psychology Coleridge A. C. Crombie J. G. Crowther Friedrich Dessauer John Dewey Albert Einstein Jacques Ellul Austin Farter Leon Festinger A. Gruenbaum Georges Gusdorf William S. Haas N. R. Hanson Ralph Hefferline E. E. Hirschmann William James Kepler John F. Kennedy Ivo Kohler Lerzch Kolakowski Alfred Korzybski K. S. Lashley Thomas Mann Simon Marcus Adolf Sperl A. Michotte George A. Miller A. J. M. Milne Oskar Morgenstern Desmond Morris S. F. Nadel Everett C. Olson R. R. Palmer A. Pannekoek William Penn Perception Rheticus Harrison E. Salisbury Th. R. Sarbin Max Scheler Hugh Seton-Watson Murray Sidman Bruno Snell P. F. Strawson W. Edgar Vinacke Waddington Basil Willey Viktor von Weizsäcker Sheldon S. Wolin (Box 25, Folder 7a)
- Series III: Manuscripts
  Series III, Manuscripts contains drafts and final copies of lectures and publications, German scientific manuscripts, speeches of introduction and thanks, patents, records of laboratory financial expenditures, poetry, notebooks, and bibliographic citations.
  The drafts and final copies of lectures and publications (25:8-43:2) have been arranged chronologically by order of composition, with undated manuscripts listed alphabetically at the end of the section. Within yearly groups, the manuscripts are arranged alphabetically by the titles given them at the time of composition. All titles are in italics except for chapter headings and untitled manuscripts, identified by first line of text, which are placed in quotation marks. Brief manuscripts of less than five pages are ordered in folders labeled "miscellaneous short manuscripts." The manuscripts have not been matched with any bibliography of Polanyi's published or unpublished writings except as an aid in determining the date of composition. Revised versions of manuscripts are placed under the date of revision and not under the date of original composition. An exception to this rule occurs when a group of manuscripts have been brought together for a specific lecture, such as occurs in 33:1-4. In such an instance, the manuscripts are organized under the date of the lecture with the date of original composition listed parenthetically.
  The remaining manuscripts (44:3-44:11) follow the drafts and final copies of lectures and publications. The German scientific manuscripts (43:3-4) are fragmentary and contain little substantive information on the scientific work of Professor Polanyi. The speeches of introduction and thanks (43:5) consist of brief remarks made by Polanyi at banquets and conferences. The patents and records of laboratory expenditures (43:6-7) contain fragmentary evidence for Polanyi's work at the Kaiser Wilhelm Institute between 1923 and 1933. The small section of poetry (43:8) holds verses by Michael Polanyi as well as poems written for him on special occasions. The nine notebooks in the collection are difficult to categorize because of diverse contents. There are four short and jumbled diaries covering the period 1926-1947 (44:1-4). In addition there are four undated notebooks (44:5) which contain brief thoughts and comments on miscellaneous authors, the English countryside, the weather, and other equally diverse subject matter. The final notebook (44:6) is an obsolete index to Professor Polanyi's correspondence files. The manuscripts series concludes with five folders of bibliographic citations.
  The earliest dated manuscripts are from 1936 and deal exclusively with economics and philosophy. There is one small group of scientific manuscripts (43:3-4,7) but they are fragmentary and indicate little about Polanyi's scientific work. The sections on science in the research notes (22:7-12) are philosophical in nature. Manuscripts such as the 1935 lectures on economics (25:9), the 1943 essays on economic planning (28:1-3), and the 1944 Principles of Economic Expansion (29:11-12) are interesting interpretations of Keynesian thought. Other manuscripts from this period like the 1938 Reflections on Marxism (25:16), the 1940 Collectivist Planning (26:3), and the 1947 Soviets and Capitalism (31:4) are criticisms of Soviet economics. By contrast, the notes contain little of relevance to Polanyi's economic thought. There are a few general notes on economic subjects (21:6) as well as material on individual economists like Keynes and von Hayek, but the majority of economic material is found in the correspondence and manuscripts.
  - Subseries 1: 1936
    - An Attitude Toward Jews and Non-Jews (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Lectures on Economics, Popular Education in Economics Suggestions for a New Research Section Visual Presentation of Social Matters (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Notes on a Film (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, Notes on the Position of Science On Reason On Truth Panic in Wall Street Science and Liberty Truth and Justice, Ideas and Belief (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Russian and Soviet Economics lecture (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Trade Cycle (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - The Working of Money: Booms and Slumps (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Untitled manuscripts, "In England 'contempt of court' is propaganda..." "One of the great English parliamentary orators..." "In 'Nature' October 30th..." "Adventure of research..." Subseries 2: 1938 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, Contemporary Problems Genetics in the U.S.S.R. Reflections on Marxism (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 3: 1939
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts and untitled manuscripts, Notes on Prejudice Review of Colin Clark, A Critique of Russian Statistics "Difficulties experienced in the past..." "It has been forcibly stated..." "Physicists say that the supreme proof..." "Science is a body of valid ideas..." (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Book plan titled The Struggle of Man in Society (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 4: 1940
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, Collectivist Planning Introductory Survey of Economic Ideas The Liberal Ideal (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, The Organization of Scientific Life Planning and Soviet Science Planning, Culture and Freedom Planning, Efficiency and Liberty Science in the U.S.S.R. Review of Eugene Varga, Two Systems (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Untitled manuscripts, "Dictatorships in Germany, Italy, and Russia..." "I think it imperative..." "Outline common principles..." "The Socialist revolution..." "While the benefits..." (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 5: 1941
    - Foundations of Freedom in Science (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - The Independence of Science (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, Commercialized Property A General Scheme of Social Mechanism Ideas and Cities The Liberal Conception of Freedom Modern Millennism (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, The New Economics Politics; Russia and Germany, April 1941 The Process of Legislation Science and Modern Civilization Science and Society Scientific Life Six Conditions for the Operation of Resources Forming Personal Property (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - The Rights and Duties of Science (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - The Social Message of Science (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Social planning lectures (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Social planning lectures (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Socialism and Liberalism Today (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Withrington League of Nations Union Lecture (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Two untitled notebooks (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 6: 1942
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, The City of Science Free Trade Through Full Employment General Will Under the Law Jewish Problems The Liberal Conception of Freedom (revised) (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Science, Welfare and the State (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Socialism Examined in Theory (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - The Structure of Freedom (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - The Structure of Freedom (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - The Structure of Freedom: Welfare (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - The Structure of Freedom: Welfare (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - The Structure of Freedom: Welfare (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - The Structure of Freedom: Welfare (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - The Structure of Freedom: Welfare (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 7: 1943
    - Economic Planning (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Economic Planning (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Liberalism and Monopoly, Draft Memo on a Planned Economy (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Limits of State Power (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Limits of State Power (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, The Autonomy of Science Cambridge discussion notes Economics of Full Employment Organization of Science Review of Harold J. Laski, Reflections on the Revolution of our Time Science and the Modern Crisis Uncertainty (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Property and Subordination in Science (manuscript and notes) (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - The Reaction from Free Trade (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Science, Ideals and Society (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Science, Ideals and Society (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Science, Ideals and Society (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Science, Ideals and Society (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Science-Its Reality and Freedom (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Science, miscellaneous manuscripts and notes (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Socialism Examined in Theory (revised) (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Socialism Examined in Theory (revised) (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Socialism Examined in Theory (revised) (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Three untitled notebooks (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 8: 1944
    - Economic Planning (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Economic Planning (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, The European Crisis Planning and Civic Liberty Reflections on John Dalton Three Periods of History Review of Erwin Schrödinger, What is Life? (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Patent Reform (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Patent Reform (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Principles of Economic Expansion, Chapter 2, "Free Trade Doctrine on Unemployment" (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Principles of Economic Expansion, Chapters 3-4, "The Reaction from Free Trade," and "The Retreat from Socialism" (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Science and the Decline of Freedom (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Science and the Modern Crisis (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 9: 1945
    - Essays on liberalism, Programme of a Liberal Philosophy The Structure of Liberalism Liberalism-Rise and Decline The Liberal & the Totalitarian Way (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts and untitled manuscripts, Applied Science Foundations of Academic Freedom Review of Ortega y Gasset, Mission of the University Notes from Broadcast to Germany Notes from Holly Royde Review of John R. Baker, Science and the Planned State The Social Message of Pure Science The Unity of Science "In 'Science' Magazine..." "The past ten years..." "The future historian..." "Among people concerned with scholarship..." (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - The Planning of Science (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Science and Welfare (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 10: 1946
    - From Adam Smith to Keynes (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - The Foundations of Freedom in Science (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - The Foundations of Freedom in Science (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, Can Science Bring Peace? The Challenge of our Time The Fall of Europe Foreign Policy and Atomic Power Freedom in Science Full Employment in a Free Economy (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts and untitled manuscripts, Notes on the Possibility of a Popular Renaissance of Spiritual Beliefs The Politics of the Atomic Age Popular Economic Problems Rededication in Germany Revolution in Economic Thought Science and the World Crisis Social Capitalism Review of Alexander Baykov, Soviet Economic System The Struggle for Moral Survival "I often wonder..." (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Principles of Economic Organization (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Science, Observation and Belief (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - The Struggle for Faith (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 11: 1947
    - The Financing of Universities (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - The Foundations of Academic Freedom (revised) (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Jewish Problems (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Memorandum on the Atomic Bomb (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, Answers to Questions at the Meeting of the Economic Reform Club British Crisis (1947-?) The Growth of Thought in Society Humanitas Inflationary Tendencies of Modern Socialism Notes on Historic Determinism Old Tasks and New Hopes (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, Over-Optimism about Russia? Science, Academic and Industrial Review of E. Ashby, Scientist in Russia Soviets and Capitalism Speech of Thanks for Honorary Degree, the University of Leeds, 14 May 1947 Two Kinds of Order The Universities Today (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Modern Science and Modern Thought (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Organization of Universities (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Political Control of Scientists (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - The Relevance of Universities (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - The Universities Today (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - What to Believe (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 12: 1948
    - Dynamic Order (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Dynamic Order (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Dynamic Order (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Economic lectures (untitled) (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, Ancestry of the Idea of Central Economic Planning Aus der Welt der Wissenschaft Education-By Whose Authority? The Free Society Review of Bertrand Russell, Human Knowledge Review of E. M. Friedwald, Man's Last Choice Michurinist Education and Achievements (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, Notes Taken in France Organization of Science Planning and Spontaneous Order Science's Part in the Spiritual Struggle Review of Hans Morgenthau, Scientific Man versus Power Politics Thinking about Thought (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - The Planning of Science, Ought Science to be Planned? (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Thought and Order (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Thought and Order (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 13: 1949
    - Can the Mind Be Represented by a Machine? (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, Review of John M. Clark, Alternative to Serfdom Review of Arthur Koestler, Insight and Outlook Review of Paul Freedman, The Principles of Scientific Research (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 14: 1950
    - The Logic of Liberty, Lectures at the University of Chicago, Lecture 1, "Perils of Inconsistency" (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - The Logic of Liberty, Lecture 3, "Freedom in Science" (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - The Logic of Liberty, Lecture 4, "The Span of Central Control" (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - The Logic of Liberty, Lecture 5, "Variants of Self-Coordination" (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - The Logic of Liberty, Lecture 6, "Polycentricity" (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - The Logic of Liberty, Lecture 7, "Critique of Freedom" (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - The Logic of Liberty, Miscellaneous manuscripts and notes (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts and untitled manuscripts, Review of Max Planck, Scientific Autobiography and Other Papers The Scientific Concept of Man Review of Barbara Wooton, Testament for Social Science "But there is a more serious sense..." (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 15: 1951
    - Manuscripts used in the Gifford Lectures. Notebooks 1-3 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Manuscripts used in the Gifford Lectures, The Law, 1942 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Manuscripts used in the Gifford Lectures, The Law, 1942 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Manuscripts used in the Gifford Lectures, Meaning, 1947, and The Structure of Liberalism, 1945 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, Review of David Mitrany, Marx Against the Peasant Review of Karl Mannheim, Freedom, Power and Democratic Planning Review of Ernest Barker, Principles of Social and Political Theory Salvation by Science (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 16: 1952
    - Miscellaneous short manuscripts, Review of Alex Weissberg, Conspiracy of Silence Review of Karl Mannheim, Essays on the Sociology of Knowledge Review of Bertrand Russell, The Impact of Science on Society Morphological Sciences Review of Erwin Schrödinger, Science and Humanism The Stability of Beliefs (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - The Policy of Full Employment (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 17: 1953